[{"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3b9", "question": "What do most lobsters and crayfish do with their shell after it has molted?", "answer": "Eat it", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fef", "question": "What is divided into 114 suras?", "answer": "The Quran", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6002447a4be4723ccac221a4", "question": "How long did it take Leonardo da Vinci to paint the Mona Lisa's smile?", "answer": "Leonardo's greatest triumph was the smile of the Mona Lisa, which he labored on for 16 years up until his death.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6014c753fbde8045e48466c1", "question": "What is the scientific name of the plant used to make liquorice?", "answer": "Glycyrrhiza glabra, the plant used to make liquorice, is native to Europe and Asia.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339513", "question": "What actor voiced Mushu in the movie \"Mulan\"?", "answer": "Eddie Murphy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a16e", "question": "Who directed the 1988 film \"Mississippi Burning\"?", "answer": "Alan Parker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cf7", "question": "What is the best known artificial international language?", "answer": "Esperanto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fede1246ce05a3942286dc2", "question": "Where is Graceland, the legendary home of Elvis Presley?", "answer": "Memphis, Tennessee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7caa1877e98cb97778a08", "question": "In which country will you find the cities Toledo and Granada?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b10e", "question": "During WWI, what disease caused 1/3 of all soldier's deaths?", "answer": "Spanish Flu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af88", "question": "What militant organization was founded in 1966 by Huey Newton and Bobby Seale?", "answer": "Black Panthers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e10", "question": "What British comedian refers to himself as an \"executive transvestite\"?", "answer": "Eddie Izzard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c84d", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the cochlea?", "answer": "The ear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396c9", "question": "The TV show \"Frasier\" is based in what US city?", "answer": "Seattle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a943", "question": "What does \"Lo Stivale\", the local name for the Italian peninsula, mean in Italian?", "answer": "The boot", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397fc", "question": "Who got to No. 3 in the UK with the song \"Joe Le Taxi\"?", "answer": "Vanessa Paradis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ace1", "question": "What were the first words Edison spoke into the phonograph he had just invented?", "answer": "Mary had a little lamb", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c77d32d24f0f7a362efd553", "question": "What is the National Animal of Mauritius?", "answer": "The Dodo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cad9", "question": "What was the common archaic name for a giraffe?", "answer": "Camelopard", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133922e", "question": "Who stars in the semi-autobiographical movie \"Purple Rain\"?", "answer": "Prince", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b31d", "question": "How many camels carried the 117,000 volumes of Abdul Kassem Ismael's library?", "answer": "400", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ca3d6944f0f6af5b06663a", "question": "What group were Gerry Rafferty and Billy Connolly in?", "answer": "The Humblebums", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f16a79f7c52aae91cc07dd", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"The Tempest\", who is the Kind of Naples?", "answer": "Alonso", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60078bd40eee65b76b9f266d", "question": "What was the name of the first English child born in the Americas?", "answer": "Virginia Dare (She was born August 18, 1587 in\u00a0Roanoke Colony.  She and about 120 settlers mysteriously disappeared.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca93", "question": "What is the study of the atmosphere called?", "answer": "Meteorology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e61", "question": "What word for a wimp comes from the title character of Harold Webster's comic strip \"The Timid Soul\"?", "answer": "Milquetoast", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133992c", "question": "What former big city mayor was the judge on \"The People\u2019s Court\" from 1997 to 1999?", "answer": "Ed Koch", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe766e3eec85e375820b28b", "question": "You can find Grand Teton National Park in which U.S. state?", "answer": "Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a982", "question": "Which island of Japan is just 26 miles form Russia at its closest point?", "answer": "Hokkaido", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a47e", "question": "What is the capital of Vermont?", "answer": "Montpelier", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdcf", "question": "Which two disciples of Jesus were called the \"Boanerges\"?", "answer": "James and John", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c1c4877e98cb9777897c", "question": "Which country has the shortest national anthem by text length?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ca3cff44f0f6af5b066636", "question": "\"Domingo\" is Spanish for what?", "answer": "Sunday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5989ac89cb8751d53e7d760a", "question": "When was the polka dot jersey first awarded at the Tour de France to the \"King of the Mountains\"?", "answer": "1975", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8d6", "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the river Rhine?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd81fdfd0de9af39e9d469a", "question": "What year did Amazon.com make its first sale?", "answer": "1995", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0b5", "question": "The March of Dimes was originally founded to help find a vaccine for what?", "answer": "Polio", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0c5", "question": "What is Frank Whittle credited with inventing?", "answer": "Turbojet engine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fb088cccf631c2414a13b5c", "question": "Which house only became one of the Great Houses of Westeros after Aegon Targaryen\u2019s invasion?", "answer": "House Tyrell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391fd", "question": "What is written on the helmet pictured in the poster for \"Full Metal Jacket\"?", "answer": "Born to kill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab04", "question": "Mount Vernon is located in which US state?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "594a633f2ebb971c1417fb98", "question": "Which Queen of England, and wife of Henry VIII, had six fingers on one of her hands?", "answer": "Anne Boleyn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a810", "question": "Zagreb is the capital of what European country?", "answer": "Croatia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ee9", "question": "In \"Uncle Tom's Cabin\", Eliza's famous flight across the ice floes takes place on what frozen river?", "answer": "The Ohio", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a53c", "question": "What four US states begin with the letter \"W\"?", "answer": "Washington, West Virginia, Wisconsin and Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7690ceec85e375820b2ab", "question": "What structure links Detroit, Michigan, and Windsor, Ontario?", "answer": "Ambassador Bridge", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefc3f26ce05a3942286f29", "question": "Colin Hay is the founder and lead vocalist for what rock band?", "answer": "Men at Work", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067ecaff9c0647b50a807e", "question": "To what age did the US state of Hawaii change the legal smoking age on January 1, 2016?", "answer": "21", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffb5ed75dad637d903c8826", "question": "What World Heritage Site's name translates to \"holy wisdom\"?", "answer": "Hagia Sophia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ef3", "question": "Which literary work's title character is named Henry Higgins?", "answer": "Pygmalion", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1c8", "question": "In 1980, what executed man was added to the Anglican Church's calendar of saint?", "answer": "Sir Thomas More", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59cdb01b65ff7d326b622a60", "question": "In which continent would you find the Atlas Mountains?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f16919f7c52aae91cc07cd", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"The Moonstone\"?", "answer": "Wilkie Collins", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe734c9eec85e375820b23c", "question": "Who chaired the \"Wannsee Conference\" during World War II?", "answer": "Reinhard Heydrich", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b086", "question": "What river did George Washington cross before the Battle of Trenton in the American Revolution?", "answer": "Delaware river", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa3ab1c73aa70ea0b70ae0", "question": "What mountain is nicknamed the \"Savage Mountain\"?", "answer": "K2 is known as the Savage Mountain due to the extreme difficulty of ascent.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c64f", "question": "What is the top layer of the Earth called?", "answer": "The Crust", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a730", "question": "What desert is home to the Saguaro Cacti?", "answer": "Sonoran Desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b17b", "question": "What year did Montenegro declare its independence from Serbia and Montenegro?", "answer": "2006", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b75", "question": "In \"Napoleon Dynamite\", what type of animal is Napoleon's grandmother's pet, Tina?", "answer": "llama", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb1fd7e83c707845b210f", "question": "Vultures gathering on the side of the road to eat are called what?", "answer": "A wake", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff51b04ff04d658268c930b", "question": "What kind of man-eating monster did Odysseus blind?", "answer": "Cyclops", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7a0", "question": "Which planet in our solar system is named after the Roman God of the sea?", "answer": "Neptune", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e67bfe83fe1f2a824bcd", "question": "What, in the 16th and 17th centuries, was a \"drunkard\u2019s cloak\"?", "answer": "It was a form of humiliation used to address people who were perceived as abusers of alcohol.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339454", "question": "Which US president presented Forrest Gump with a Medal of Honour?", "answer": "Lyndon B. Johnson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b42f", "question": "At what age did Alfred Hitchcock die?", "answer": "80", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff513b4ff04d658268c92de", "question": "What naval battle between Mark Antony and Octavian is often said to mark the beginning of the Roman Empire?", "answer": "The\u00a0Battle of Actium", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133896b", "question": "What is the better-known name of crime fiction writer Lady Mallowan D.B.E.?", "answer": "Agatha Christie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf34", "question": "In Scotland what was the tawse?", "answer": "Teachers Strap or belt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad9db2ce748bb36357acdd7", "question": "On the Apollo 11 mission, what is the name of the man who never walked on the Moon?", "answer": "Michael Collins", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be5e", "question": "What North American Soccer League team signed Pele in 1975?", "answer": "The New York Cosmos", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fed2ba2ec223966ae8f890f", "question": "On what avenue does the traditional New York City Easter Parade and Bonnet Festival take place?", "answer": "Fifth Avenue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d33c2596a59cbdfbd399", "question": "Which capital name means \"City of Joy\"?", "answer": "Bucharest", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecdcefec223966ae8f88fa", "question": "Which Christmas song was the second piece of music broadcast on the radio?", "answer": "\"O Holy Night\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a2246c0f9723ab15cb3f", "question": "Why did humans almost go extinct in 70,000 B.C.?", "answer": "Volcanic eruption", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ec22b48dc25ca9e12ef62a", "question": "Which French singer and actor sings the theme song to Disney's film \"The Aristocats\"?", "answer": "Maurice Chevalier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b328", "question": "What state did Harry Truman represent as a US Senator before becoming President of the Unites States?", "answer": "Missouri", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133917f", "question": "Who is the Kindergarten Cop?", "answer": "Arnold Schwarzenneger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ccf7c47b37b32637bdc44c8", "question": "What is the smallest country by area and population?", "answer": "Vatican City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad3e", "question": "The \"Pentagon Papers\" contained secret government information about what?", "answer": "The Vietnam War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133958e", "question": "What is Ben Stiller's character's last name in the movie \"Meet the Parents\"?", "answer": "Focker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59da1af6f6756c9b30ba14f4", "question": "In which film did a Rolls Royce have the number plate AU1?", "answer": "Goldfinger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010c7130775fa611bce67d5", "question": "What does the Latin phrase \"Sic semper tyrannis\" mean?", "answer": "\"Thus always to tyrants\" -- It is short for \"Sic semper tyrannis ad mortem\", which means \"Thus always I bring death to tyrants\".", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febb68b7e83c707845b2128", "question": "What color of star has the hottest surface temperature?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133955e", "question": "Who is the star of the \"Tomb Raider\" video games?", "answer": "Lara Croft", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339635", "question": "Which Disney's cartoon character's love interest is named Jasmine?", "answer": "Aladdin's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abd5", "question": "What is the capital of Cyprus?", "answer": "Nicosia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601601a2fe83fe1f2a824c60", "question": "In what year were women first allowed to participate in the modern Olympic games?", "answer": "1900 -- in Paris", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3db", "question": "What was the four letter name of Thailand before 1949?", "answer": "Siam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b64", "question": "What was the name of Danny's gang on the movie \"Grease\"?", "answer": "The Thunderbirds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc1c", "question": "What was New York Yankees original name?", "answer": "New York Highlanders", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad91", "question": "Who changed Blixem's name to Blitzen in his 1844, A Visit from St. Nicholas?", "answer": "Clement Moore", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339332", "question": "In what year did the TV show \"The Hills\" premier on TV?", "answer": "2007", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f5f", "question": "\"Typo\" is short for what two-word term?", "answer": "Typographical error", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b53d", "question": "What does the word \"honcho\" mean in Japanese?", "answer": "Squad Leader", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeef", "question": "Who commanded the English Fleet against the Spanish Armada in 1588?", "answer": "Admiral Charles Howard", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cb9", "question": "Which character is the only survivor of Ahab's ship at the end of \"Moby Dick\"?", "answer": "Ishmael", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c701", "question": "What is the atomic number of gold?", "answer": "79", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5f1", "question": "The planet Uranus was originally named what?", "answer": "George's Star", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adf2", "question": "When did the Hindenburg airship disaster occur?", "answer": "1937", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f9f3f3eaf848b908361b86b", "question": "What amusement ride was first ridden in 1893 at the World's Columbian Exposition in Chicago?", "answer": "The Ferris Wheel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e67", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Winnie-the-Pooh?", "answer": "Sterling Holloway", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb2af65ff7d326b622a77", "question": "Mycophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Mushrooms", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f7d", "question": "What was Bruce Hornsby's backing band?", "answer": "The Range", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a309", "question": "Who played the role of Karen on the TV show \"Californication\"?", "answer": "Natascha McElhone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601debe96b1208747aa7e9d7", "question": "Which famous entrepreneur is credited with inventing the weekend?", "answer": "Henry Ford", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c62b8540ae4aacefc17eee0", "question": "Who are the Pines twins in the TV show \"Gravity Falls\"?", "answer": "Dipper and Mabel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beba", "question": "What Thames River town lent its name to the collarless polo shirts first worn by its rowing team?", "answer": "Henley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b831", "question": "What city is home to Amazon.com's headquarters?", "answer": "Seattle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe766d6eec85e375820b28a", "question": "Which fruit is called \"halakahiki\" in Hawaiian and has been grown in Hawaii since the early 1800's?", "answer": "Pineapples", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ae", "question": "The Great Pee Dee River flows into what body of water?", "answer": "Atlantic Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea7dfbff048f679a45ac04", "question": "Arithmophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Numbers", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf37", "question": "Papaphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "The pope", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b866", "question": "What chess piece makes an L-shaped move?", "answer": "Knight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af7f", "question": "During what war did Benedict Arnold become a traitor to the American people?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339009", "question": "What is the more common name for serigraphy?", "answer": "Screen printing", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6014c578fbde8045e48466ad", "question": "A group of otters is called what?", "answer": "A raft", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7cc", "question": "What is a traditional karate uniform called?", "answer": "Gi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062c0dc9d816e292245c28", "question": "What art movement was Yoko Ono associated with during the 1960s?", "answer": "Yoko Ono helped to define the\u00a0Fluxus\u00a0movement in 1960s  New York, which was part Dada, part Bauhaus and part Zen.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea7ca1ff048f679a45abf8", "question": "What do you call a group of giraffes?", "answer": "A tower", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adc6", "question": "What were slaves called in ancient Sparta?", "answer": "Helots", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e7b", "question": "During what war was the novel \"The African Queen\" set?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad99", "question": "What decades was the Zodiac Killer active in the US?", "answer": "1960s and 1970s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf8f", "question": "The \"Intelligent Whale\" was the nickname of an early what?", "answer": "Submarine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea43f3ff048f679a45ab8b", "question": "What is the name of the submerged fringe of a continent?", "answer": "Continental Shelf", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc1f", "question": "Which building houses the world's biggest four-faced chiming clock?", "answer": "Minneapolis City Hall", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9b9", "question": "The zodiac sign \"Cancer\" refers to what animal?", "answer": "Crab", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59636f3c967692ea851899b5", "question": "The average American will eat 35,000 what in a lifetime?", "answer": "Cookies", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe76faeeec85e375820b2ee", "question": "Where was the first European town in the Americas built?", "answer": "Dominican Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e72cf19d0874f1a5e2d1c29", "question": "How much liquid can be placed in a 10 gallon hat?", "answer": "3/4 of a gallon (US)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdfb933003d27d341092bc2", "question": "Where is King Tut\u2019s tomb?", "answer": "Valley of the Kings", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c547", "question": "Who averaged one invention patent for every two weeks of his working life?", "answer": "Thomas Edison", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a724", "question": "What two rivers meet in Nebraska to form the Platte River?", "answer": "North Platte River and South Platte River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e42", "question": "What slave name does Kunta Kinte's owner force him to adopt in Alex Haley's \"Roots\"?", "answer": "Toby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6661ca5bfecdd737e0865", "question": "Where is Apple Inc. headquartered?", "answer": "Cupertino, California", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59071cfb3745b36be73039d2", "question": "Who is credited with inventing the V-2 rocket for Nazi Germany and later the Saturn V rocket for the United States?", "answer": "Wernher von Braun", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9e8", "question": "What year did the Gran Turismo game series first debut?", "answer": "1997", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b167", "question": "What architect is largely credited with having designed Elizabeth Tower, also known as Big Ben?", "answer": "Augustus Pugin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59675d002b59efe0e9417e96", "question": "The color of your tongue is pink only if it's what?", "answer": "Germ-free", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b385", "question": "How was the country of Belize known prior to 1973?", "answer": "British Honduras", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec88caec223966ae8f8823", "question": "Which pop media icon was recently memorialized in \"World of Warcraft\" in late 2018?", "answer": "Stan Lee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ed1e08d98002fdd633c4", "question": "The 1976 Summer Olympics were held in which city?", "answer": "Montreal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe65f3a1f3c0ead6880d636", "question": "What U.S. President coined the phrase \"Good to the last drop\", referring to coffee?", "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffb60975dad637d903c882b", "question": "Catalonia is a region of what country?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca9b", "question": "Sophophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Learning or knowledge", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339746", "question": "Who played Louie De Palma in the TV series \"Taxi\"?", "answer": "Danny DeVito", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133935c", "question": "In what city did the TV show \"Full House\" take place?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c68a", "question": "Ranger VII was the first US spacecraft to send back pictures of what?", "answer": "The moon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adce", "question": "At which battle was poison gas first used?", "answer": "Second Battle of Ypres", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b868", "question": "What drink's Gaelic name means \"water of life\"?", "answer": "Whiskey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fbae45a0738315b1fb74e1e", "question": "Who scored the first goal at original Wembley Stadium?", "answer": "David Jack", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdbd", "question": "What is traditionally the main fruit ingredient in Black Forest cake?", "answer": "Cherries", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339450", "question": "How did the children die in the 2001 movie \"The Others\"?", "answer": "Suffocation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393a9", "question": "Who plays Richard Gere's lawyer in the movie \"Pretty Woman\"?", "answer": "Jason Alexander", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef93396ce05a3942286e8b", "question": "Frank Darabont seriously contemplated selling the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\" script to which person?", "answer": "Rob Reiner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cfc", "question": "In which movie did Ione Skye portray a witch?", "answer": "Four Rooms", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe12f35e39efa6330e0fed7", "question": "Where is the world's shortest commercial runway?", "answer": "Saba", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d6", "question": "Which countries does France share a land border with?", "answer": "Spain, Luxembourg, Belgium, Switzerland, Monaco, Andorra, Germany and Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd66188a5bfecdd737e083c", "question": "Whose massively popular photo led to the creation of Google Images?", "answer": "Jennifer Lopez", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe0e396fcbed638185eaa23", "question": "The first picture postcard was invented in which country?", "answer": "England", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abda", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Michigan?", "answer": "Lansing", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdf6", "question": "John the Baptist survived in the wilderness by eating locusts and what other food?", "answer": "Wild honey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b49", "question": "Where did the Pied Piper play?", "answer": "Hamelin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf1a", "question": "What is the colour of mourning in Turkey?", "answer": "Violet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea7da1ff048f679a45abfa", "question": "Achluophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Darkness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bae", "question": "Which Beethoven symphony became associated with victory in WWII?", "answer": "The Fifth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b358ab15db0d66a186cb554", "question": "From which state does the US band \"The Great Divide\" originate?", "answer": "Oklahoma", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b637", "question": "What was the first name of the real Chef Boyardee?", "answer": "Hector", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b811", "question": "What country gave the world porcelain?", "answer": "China", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ab99bbc21a8909e5c332d2f", "question": "What novel was the 1988 film \"Who Framed Roger Rabbit\" loosely based on?", "answer": "Who Censored Roger Rabbit?", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ab6", "question": "Who wrote, TIdings of Comfort and Joy in 1997?", "answer": "T. Davis Bunn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339773", "question": "What is the name of the demons in Hellraiser?", "answer": "Cenobites", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c970", "question": "What is an organism called that lives on or in a host animal?", "answer": "Parasite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cd8", "question": "According to J.K. Rowling, in what year was Albus Dumbledore born?", "answer": "1881", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b84d", "question": "What is the Hebrew word for peace, used as both a greeting and a farewell?", "answer": "Shalom", "category": "general"}, {"id": "596761bf2b59efe0e9417ea4", "question": "The 13 stripes on the US Flag represent what?", "answer": "The 13 original colonies", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d118d64fea7fe947a22289", "question": "Which years marked Bjorn Borg's successive Wimbledon titles?", "answer": "1976 to 1980", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef92646ce05a3942286e82", "question": "Who created \"The Sopranos\"?", "answer": "David Chase", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5db", "question": "Which mega city's name translated means \"Eastern Capital\"?", "answer": "Tokyo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339138", "question": "Whose alias is \"The Man of Bronze\" in popular literature?", "answer": "Doc Savage", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600cc46f6de0eb824d4052f3", "question": "Which African country was formerly known as Abyssinia?", "answer": "Ethiopia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefa6f06ce05a3942286ecd", "question": "In the film \"Fargo\", Jerry Lundegaard was captured by the police in what city?", "answer": "Bismarck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8eff201dd7bf43be5e7f7", "question": "Which beauty supply company started out selling dental supplies?", "answer": "OPI", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa3df6ce05a3942286eac", "question": "Which Oscar-winner studied opera as a teen?", "answer": "Meryl Streep", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb40365ff7d326b622a83", "question": "What year was Budweiser first introduced?", "answer": "1876", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab1ad1baab681b09292197", "question": "Which car is considered to be the first hot hatchback, introduced in the 1970s?", "answer": "The Simca 1100 TI", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a1", "question": "In what state was the TV show \"B.J. and the Bear\" set?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c90cf1f52800b05cac20f07", "question": "What US state receives the most annual rainfall?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b93", "question": "Frank Sinatra died on the exact same night as the series finale of what popular TV show?", "answer": "Seinfeld", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff512bfff04d658268c92d3", "question": "What doctrine stated the policy of the U.S. regarding European colonialism in the Americas?", "answer": "Monroe Doctrine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b571bdc67df192a942e336e", "question": "What is the name of the farm in the book \"Animal Farm\"?", "answer": "Manor Farm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393c0", "question": "What Al Pacino movie portrayed a bank robbery on August 22, 1972?", "answer": "Dog Day Afternoon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab00", "question": "What stretch of water lies between New Brunswick, Maine and Nova Scotia?", "answer": "Bay of Fundy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b81f", "question": "What was the first mass produced game to use people as playing pieces?", "answer": "Twister", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5da", "question": "Which country deliberately introduced myxomatosis to reduce its rabbit population?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392cf", "question": "What film stars Bruce Willis as a plastic surgeon Ernest Menville?", "answer": "Death Becomes Her", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8ad0b01dd7bf43be5e774", "question": "What color was long considered the color of royalty?", "answer": "Purple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fae", "question": "Who composed the music for the opera \"The Tales of Hoffman\"?", "answer": "Jacques Offenbach", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeed", "question": "Which states did the US gain as a result of the Mexican-American War?", "answer": "New Mexico, California and Texas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e48", "question": "What word do we derive from the Salish Indian word for \"wild man\"?", "answer": "Sasquatch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb70", "question": "Who led the NFL in rushing yards four out of five years from 1972 to 1976?", "answer": "O.J. Simpson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c072", "question": "What is the Shaddock a variety of?\u00a0", "answer": "Citrus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a5530b3e1c6f9840ba31a0", "question": "Which band recorded the album \"Fly Like an Eagle\" in 1975 to 1976?", "answer": "Steve Miller Band", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac77", "question": "When was the modern tire first introduced to the market?", "answer": "1887", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a80", "question": "In the Foreigner song \"Hot Blooded\", the singer has a temperature of how many degrees?", "answer": "103", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5971e10289261e916c8e09b1", "question": "Which European city is the game \"Assassins Creed Unity\" set in?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa86a6ce05a3942286ed0", "question": "Who was originally to be cast as Axel Foley in the film \"Beverly Hills Cop\"?", "answer": "Sylvester Stallone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600cc0666de0eb824d4052d9", "question": "What is the most populous city in Australia?", "answer": "Sidney", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c704", "question": "What is the only chemical element whose name is only three letters long?", "answer": "Tin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea364aff048f679a45ab0b", "question": "Carrots are a good source of which vitamin?", "answer": "A", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c50f", "question": "What is the only fruit to have its seeds on the outside?", "answer": "Strawberry", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a841", "question": "The ancient city of Troy was located in what is now what country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015ee33fe83fe1f2a824c07", "question": "David Jung is considered by many to be the originator of which famous food?", "answer": "Fortune cookies", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c584", "question": "By what common household name is sodium chloride better known?", "answer": "Salt", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399b9", "question": "What actor played the role of Newman in the TV show \"Seinfeld\"?", "answer": "Wayne Knight", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dfa", "question": "What is the Roman name of the Greek goddess Aphrodite?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a29b", "question": "Which English director founded the Theatre Workshop?", "answer": "Joan Littlewood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a14f", "question": "What city do Batman and Robin patrol?", "answer": "Gotham City", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d4e", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"The Girl in the Kremlin\"?", "answer": "Natalie Darryl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec23308dc25ca9e12ef62e", "question": "What color does a chameleon turn when its trying to warm up?", "answer": "Black", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e0c7fe83fe1f2a824b91", "question": "What were the first two Western countries that the Nazis invaded during World War II?", "answer": "Norway and Denmark", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b13c", "question": "In what year did Joseph Smith first organize the Mormon Church?", "answer": "1830", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399eb", "question": "How many of the seven dwarfs had mustaches?", "answer": "None", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b68", "question": "On what cartoon do the main characters live in the fictional town of Bikini Bottom?", "answer": "SpongeBob SquarePants", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad55", "question": "Who was the only son born to Henry Ford that bears his name?", "answer": "Edsel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbc3", "question": "What piece on a chess board can only move on one color?", "answer": "Bishop", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcb3", "question": "What kind of fruit juice is used to mix a Bronx Cocktail?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062ba7c9d816e292245c22", "question": "What is the name of Captain Ahab's ship?", "answer": "The Pequod", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe12e58e39efa6330e0fed2", "question": "Which US state has the most lighthouses?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aad2", "question": "Which European city is nicknamed \"The Eternal City\"?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d50", "question": "What oddly worded catchphrase earned Whitney Houston a \"Big Quote\" nomination from VH-1 in 2005?", "answer": "Hell to the no!", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339193", "question": "Who is the villain in Disney's \"101 Dalmatians\" animated adaptation?", "answer": "Cruella de Vil", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c20a", "question": "Which country was selected as a host of the 1916 Olympic Games, but didn't actually host them?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c8a83b90aac110e416708c", "question": "Who said \"He that drinks his cider alone, let him catch his horse alone.\"?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a039", "question": "What is Quagmire's daughter's name in the TV show \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "Anna Lee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab977986faa38a764be529", "question": "On what vehicle was the Mutt Cutts Van based on in the 1994 film \"Dumb and Dumber\"?", "answer": "1984 Ford Econoline", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af61", "question": "Which prison was Nelson Mandela released from?", "answer": "Victor Verster", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392a8", "question": "Whose California grave marker reads \"1935 - 1998 And the Beat Goes On?\"", "answer": "Sonny Bono's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ba7", "question": "Who played Willis on the sitcom \"Diff'rent Strokes\"?", "answer": "Todd Bridges", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b935", "question": "What are you shopping for if you're sized up by a Brannock device?", "answer": "Shoes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b54a", "question": "What is the highest hand in straight Poker?", "answer": "A royal flush", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c8a84290aac110e416708d", "question": "Who said \"He that drinks his cider alone, let him catch his horse alone.\"?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c566", "question": "How many ounces are there in a pound?", "answer": "16", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c24d", "question": "Do sea gulls drink sea water?", "answer": "Yes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b09a", "question": "Which English King signed the Magna Carta in 1215?", "answer": "King John", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe658b7ae7e414034b5aef6", "question": "Who were the two leaders of Chile's Independence movement from 1810 until 1818?", "answer": "Bernardo O'Higgins And Jose De San Martin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c673", "question": "Jonas Salk discovered a vaccine for what disease?", "answer": "Polio", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b499", "question": "Which country were the 1908 Summer Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "United Kingdom", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5937ef0108d98002fdd633dc", "question": "What is a person with numerophobia afraid of?", "answer": "Numbers or mathematics", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aff3", "question": "In 1911, what entrepreneur retired as president of Standard Oil?", "answer": "John Davison Rockefeller", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ad8", "question": "In \"The Twelve Days of Christmas\", what did my true love send to me on the sixth day?", "answer": "Six geese-a-laying", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a567", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Sooner State\"?", "answer": "Oklahoma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fde52fac6c6b019850c9a99", "question": "Who was arrested after killing 35 people on the Australian island of Tasmania in 1996?", "answer": "Martin Bryant", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7ead2b24f84e0b9f9ffd8", "question": "By what collective name were Steve Cropper, Lewie Steinberg, Donald \"Duck\" Dunn, and Al Jackson Jr. known?", "answer": "The Mg's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c269", "question": "What science deals with the motion of projectiles?", "answer": "Ballistics", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597cddcae347d002c297e4f4", "question": "Who played the lead in the movie \"The Mask\"?", "answer": "Jim Carrey", "category": "entertainment"}]